<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-08-27T11:29:08+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Future of Music Technology: My Vision and Journey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/insights/2025/future-of-music-technology/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Future of Music Technology: My Vision and Journey"/><published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/insights/2025/future-of-music-technology</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/insights/2025/future-of-music-technology/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2> <p>As I stand at the threshold of my university journey, preparing to dive deeper into the world of music technology, I find myself reflecting on the incredible evolution I’ve witnessed in the intersection of music and technology. From my early days at Yamaha Music School to performing on international stages, technology has been both my tool and my companion in musical expression.</p> <h2 id="the-evolution-of-my-musical-technology-journey">The Evolution of My Musical Technology Journey</h2> <h3 id="early-foundations-the-electone-experience">Early Foundations: The Electone Experience</h3> <p>My relationship with music technology began with the Yamaha Electone—an instrument that, at first glance, might seem like a traditional keyboard but is actually a sophisticated digital orchestra. The Electone taught me that technology isn’t meant to replace human creativity; it’s meant to amplify it.</p> <p>Through the Electone, I learned to:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Layer multiple instrumental voices</strong> to create rich, complex arrangements</li> <li><strong>Program and manipulate rhythms</strong> in real-time during performances</li> <li><strong>Blend traditional and digital sounds</strong> to create unique sonic landscapes</li> <li><strong>Think orchestrally</strong> while performing as a soloist</li> </ul> <h3 id="compositional-evolution-from-traditional-to-technological">Compositional Evolution: From Traditional to Technological</h3> <p>My compositions have evolved alongside my understanding of technology:</p> <p><strong>2015-2017: The Foundation Years</strong></p> <ul> <li><em>Spring Dance</em> and <em>Beautiful Huitengxile</em> focused on melody and harmony</li> <li>Simple use of Electone’s basic features</li> <li>Traditional composition approach with technological assistance</li> </ul> <p><strong>2018-2020: The Exploration Phase</strong></p> <ul> <li><em>Skyline</em> and <em>New Beginning</em> incorporated more complex soundscapes</li> <li>Experimentation with layered textures and dynamic programming</li> <li>Growing understanding of how technology can enhance storytelling</li> </ul> <p><strong>2021-Present: The Integration Era</strong></p> <ul> <li><em>The Battle of Gai Xia</em> demonstrates full integration of narrative and technology</li> <li>Complex orchestration using digital instruments to simulate full orchestras</li> <li>Real-time sound manipulation as part of the performance art</li> </ul> <h2 id="the-current-landscape-of-music-technology">The Current Landscape of Music Technology</h2> <p>Today’s music technology landscape is incredibly exciting. We’re seeing:</p> <h3 id="ai-and-machine-learning-in-composition">AI and Machine Learning in Composition</h3> <ul> <li>Tools like AIVA and Amper Music are creating new possibilities for collaboration between humans and AI</li> <li>Machine learning algorithms can analyze musical patterns and suggest harmonizations</li> <li>AI-assisted mastering and mixing are democratizing high-quality production</li> </ul> <h3 id="spatial-audio-and-immersive-experiences">Spatial Audio and Immersive Experiences</h3> <ul> <li>Dolby Atmos and binaural audio are creating new dimensions in music</li> <li>VR and AR performances are redefining what a “concert” can be</li> <li>3D audio positioning allows composers to place sounds in physical space</li> </ul> <h3 id="real-time-collaboration-technologies">Real-Time Collaboration Technologies</h3> <ul> <li>Cloud-based DAWs enable global collaboration</li> <li>Low-latency networks make remote ensemble performances possible</li> <li>Blockchain technology is revolutionizing music rights and distribution</li> </ul> <h2 id="my-vision-for-the-future">My Vision for the Future</h2> <p>As someone who has grown up bridging traditional musical training with technological innovation, I envision a future where:</p> <h3 id="technology-enhances-human-expression">Technology Enhances Human Expression</h3> <p>Rather than replacing musicians, technology should amplify our ability to express complex emotions and ideas. I see AI as a collaborative partner that can:</p> <ul> <li>Suggest harmonies that human composers might not consider</li> <li>Generate variations on themes for exploration</li> <li>Handle technical aspects of production, freeing artists to focus on creativity</li> </ul> <h3 id="accessibility-through-innovation">Accessibility Through Innovation</h3> <p>Technology can make music creation accessible to more people:</p> <ul> <li>Gesture-based controllers for those with physical limitations</li> <li>AI-powered learning systems that adapt to individual learning styles</li> <li>Real-time translation of musical ideas across different instrumental interfaces</li> </ul> <h3 id="cultural-preservation-and-evolution">Cultural Preservation and Evolution</h3> <p>Music technology can help preserve traditional music while enabling its evolution:</p> <ul> <li>Digital archiving of rare instruments and performance techniques</li> <li>AI models trained on traditional music can help create respectful contemporary variations</li> <li>Global collaboration platforms can facilitate cross-cultural musical exchange</li> </ul> <h2 id="challenges-and-ethical-considerations">Challenges and Ethical Considerations</h2> <p>With great technological power comes responsibility. Key challenges include:</p> <h3 id="authenticity-and-artistic-integrity">Authenticity and Artistic Integrity</h3> <ul> <li>How do we maintain the human soul in increasingly technological music?</li> <li>When does technological assistance become replacement?</li> <li>How do we preserve the value of traditional musical skills?</li> </ul> <h3 id="accessibility-vs-exclusivity">Accessibility vs. Exclusivity</h3> <ul> <li>High-end music technology can create new barriers to entry</li> <li>The digital divide affects who can participate in modern music creation</li> <li>We must ensure technological advancement doesn’t exclude traditional approaches</li> </ul> <h3 id="intellectual-property-in-the-digital-age">Intellectual Property in the Digital Age</h3> <ul> <li>AI-generated music raises questions about authorship and ownership</li> <li>Sampling and remixing technologies challenge traditional copyright concepts</li> <li>New frameworks are needed for collaborative human-AI creation</li> </ul> <h2 id="my-academic-and-professional-goals">My Academic and Professional Goals</h2> <h3 id="short-term-objectives-university-years">Short-term Objectives (University Years)</h3> <ol> <li><strong>Technical Foundation</strong>: Master programming languages relevant to music technology (Python, Max/MSP, Pure Data)</li> <li><strong>Interdisciplinary Learning</strong>: Combine music theory with computer science, acoustics, and psychology</li> <li><strong>Collaborative Projects</strong>: Work with computer science students on innovative music applications</li> <li><strong>Research Experience</strong>: Participate in research on AI-assisted composition or spatial audio</li> </ol> <h3 id="long-term-vision-post-graduation">Long-term Vision (Post-Graduation)</h3> <ol> <li><strong>Industry Innovation</strong>: Contribute to the development of next-generation music creation tools</li> <li><strong>Educational Impact</strong>: Develop accessible music technology education programs</li> <li><strong>Cultural Bridge</strong>: Create technologies that bridge Western and Eastern musical traditions</li> <li><strong>Entrepreneurial Ventures</strong>: Launch startups focused on democratizing music creation</li> </ol> <h2 id="the-role-of-traditional-training-in-a-technological-future">The Role of Traditional Training in a Technological Future</h2> <p>My classical training at Yamaha Music School isn’t obsolete in our technological age—it’s essential. Traditional musical training provides:</p> <h3 id="foundational-understanding">Foundational Understanding</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Musical theory</strong> gives structure to technological experimentation</li> <li><strong>Performance skills</strong> ensure that technology serves musical expression, not the reverse</li> <li><strong>Cultural knowledge</strong> prevents technology from homogenizing musical traditions</li> </ul> <h3 id="human-centered-design">Human-Centered Design</h3> <ul> <li>Understanding how musicians think and work is crucial for designing useful tools</li> <li>Empathy for the creative process ensures technology enhances rather than hinders creativity</li> <li>Real performance experience identifies practical needs that pure technologists might miss</li> </ul> <h2 id="conclusion-a-harmonious-future">Conclusion: A Harmonious Future</h2> <p>As I prepare to embark on formal studies in music technology, I’m excited about the possibilities ahead. The future of music lies not in choosing between tradition and innovation, but in finding the perfect harmony between them.</p> <p>My journey from a three-year-old discovering melodies at Yamaha Music School to a high school senior preparing for university has taught me that the best technology is invisible—it serves the music, not the other way around. My goal is to contribute to a future where technology amplifies human creativity, preserves cultural traditions, and makes music creation accessible to all.</p> <p>The intersection of music and technology is where I want to make my mark—not as someone who chooses one over the other, but as someone who helps them sing in perfect harmony.</p> <hr/> <p><em>This reflection represents my current thinking as I prepare for university studies in music technology. I’m eager to deepen these ideas through formal academic study and collaborative research with fellow students and faculty who share this passion for the future of music.</em></p>]]></content><author><name>JiaWen Wu</name></author><category term="music-technology"/><category term="composition"/><category term="future"/><category term="innovation"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reflecting on how technology is reshaping music creation and my role as a future music technologist.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello, world!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/insights/2025/helloworld/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello, world!"/><published>2025-08-25T21:53:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-08-25T21:53:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/insights/2025/helloworld</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/insights/2025/helloworld/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="hello-world">Hello, world!</h1> <h2 id="hello-world---heading-2">hello world - heading 2</h2> <p>hello world–text</p> <h3 id="hello-world---heading-3">hello world - heading 3</h3> <h4 id="hello-world---heading-4">hello world - heading 4</h4> <p>hello world–text</p> <blockquote> <p>I discovered, too, that a great pleasure, an enjoyment which the horizon only bounded, lay all outside the high and spike-guarded walls of our garden: this pleasure consisted in prospect of noble summits girdling a great hill-hollow, rich in verdure and shadow; in a bright beck, full of dark stones and sparkling edges. How different had this scene looked when I viewed it laid out beneath the iron sky of winter, stiffened in frost, shrouded with snow! —when mists as chill as death wandered to the impulse of east winds along those purple peaks, and rolled down “ing” and holm till they blended with the frozen fog of the beck! That beck itself was then a torrent, turbid and curbless; it tore asunder the wood, and sent a raving sound through the air, often thickened with wild rain or whirling sleet; and for the forest on its banks, that showed only ranks of skeletons.</p> </blockquote> <div class="language-java highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="kd">public</span> <span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nc">hello</span><span class="o">{</span>
    <span class="kd">public</span> <span class="kd">static</span> <span class="kt">void</span> <span class="nf">main</span> <span class="o">(</span><span class="nc">String</span> <span class="n">args</span><span class="o">[]){</span>
        <span class="nc">System</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">out</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">println</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="s">"Hello. world!"</span><span class="o">);</span>
    <span class="o">}</span>
<span class="o">}</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <div class="language-python highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nf">print</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">Hello, World!</span><span class="sh">"</span><span class="p">)</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p><img src="/assets/img/posts/helloworld/helloworld.png" alt="helloworld"/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Helloworld"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A deep dive into the circuitry and design philosophy that gives the legendary Minimoog its timeless sound.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction of Yamaha Electone Festivel (YEF)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/insights/2024/intro-to-yef/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction of Yamaha Electone Festivel (YEF)"/><published>2024-08-25T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-25T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/insights/2024/intro-to-yef</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/insights/2024/intro-to-yef/"><![CDATA[<p>Y.E.F．全称为雅马哈双排键电子琴音乐节(YAMAHA ELECTONE FESTIVAL)，是由日本雅马哈公司主办，亚太地区部分国家和地区分别承办的双排键活动赛事，每年选拔出来的选手将轮流在各国或地区集中参赛。此活动的宗旨是：通过舞台的实际演出，提供双排键爱好者和学习者共同交流的平台，并选拔出优秀的双排键演奏者，发掘其成为音乐家的可能性。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Music"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A brief introduction to the Yamaha Electone Festival (YEF).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">YEF Experience</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/insights/2023/yef-experience/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="YEF Experience"/><published>2023-08-25T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-25T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/insights/2023/yef-experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/insights/2023/yef-experience/"><![CDATA[<p>2023年，是让我开拓国际视野的一年，也是令我难忘的一年。我非常荣幸能够入选YEF Grand Final一般部门全球总决赛。一般部门及成人组别，包含16岁及以上的所有选手，大多数来自专业院校以及其毕业的学生，而我在接到决赛通知的时候，只有15岁。同时，我也是新赛制后，中国首位入选一般部门总决赛的选手。决赛主要分为两个部分：课题曲和自由曲。课题曲是给定一段旋律，要求完成编曲以发展成一个4分钟以内的曲子；自由曲要求必须是原创曲目或者原创编曲。可见，YEF不仅仅较量的是双排键演奏的演奏技术，更是音乐创新创造能力以及音乐素养的比拼。 这对我确实是一次非常大的挑战。因为毫无经验，一切都只能自己摸索。我首先需要的，便是合理高效地安排备赛时间。我找到班主任林老师和周慧副校长，申请利用每周社团活动的时间准备比赛。慧校全力支持，并协调社团负责张茅老师、社团团长李若菡帮我把社团活动和备赛内容相结合，使我可以兼顾。可以说，学校给予了我最需要的时间支持和精神支持。有了学校的支持，我便开始漫长的备赛过程。我的音乐专业老师陈老师指导我完善曲子、改进演奏技术。她给予我的，是专业知识和技能的支持。在决赛1月27日前的一个月，课题曲目公布。恰逢期末考试，我感受到前所未有的压力。为了能够完成我对音乐的追求，我几乎每天都睡得很晚很晚。期末考试结束之后，我全力冲刺，经常和老师沟通交流到深夜。那些天我每天近8个小时的持续练习，竭尽所能，完成编曲，为我的决赛铺路。 在日本东京比赛的当天，我非常紧张，甚至连饭都吃不下。等到主持人慢慢退下，我迈着坚定的步伐上台，耳朵里全都是我呼吸的声音。然而，我坐在琴上的那一刻，我突然感觉整个世界都安静了。手指放在琴键上，慢慢的，我的内心与琴键紧紧的连接起来了。学习音乐13年，我追求的那种享受终于降临在我身上。我用一个个连续有活力的音符，将两首曲子一气呵成地演奏出来，将我内心对于音乐的理解，那份热爱与追求倾诉出来。直到抬手结束，我的思绪依然沉浸在演奏当中。那一刻，我由衷地笑了，因为名次之于我，已经不重要了。我在音乐路上13年所追求的那种享受舞台的状态，在这次，完美地成为现实！YEF的舞台是我心目中梦想的舞台，没有什么比享受这个舞台重要，没有什么比享受音乐重要！从之前的万分紧张，到这一次淋漓尽致的音乐表现，足以见证我的成长，足以诠释这次比赛的意义！ 伴随我整个学期的2023YEF圆满的画上一个句号。回想这段路途，从7月的落地赛到1月的总决赛，心里真的有一种说不出来的感觉。谢谢大家一路的关心和支持！无论是来自父母和老师的指导、教诲，还是来自北京中学国际部同学们的每一声鼓励和支持。当然，我也要感谢我自己。谢谢我无数个深夜的坚持，谢谢我对音乐那至死不渝的热爱。这次YEF绝对不仅仅是一次比赛，它是我生命中闪闪发光的一笔！</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Music"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2023年，是让我开拓国际视野的一年，也是令我难忘的一年。我非常荣幸能够入选YEF Grand Final一般部门全球总决赛。一般部门及成人组别，包含16岁及以上的所有选手，大多数来自专业院校以及其毕业的学生，而我在接到决赛通知的时候，只有15岁。同时，我也是新赛制后，中国首位入选一般部门总决赛的选手。决赛主要分为两个部分：课题曲和自由曲。课题曲是给定一段旋律，要求完成编曲以发展成一个4分钟以内的曲子；自由曲要求必须是原创曲目或者原创编曲。可见，YEF不仅仅较量的是双排键演奏的演奏技术，更是音乐创新创造能力以及音乐素养的比拼。 这对我确实是一次非常大的挑战。因为毫无经验，一切都只能自己摸索。我首先需要的，便是合理高效地安排备赛时间。我找到班主任林老师和周慧副校长，申请利用每周社团活动的时间准备比赛。慧校全力支持，并协调社团负责张茅老师、社团团长李若菡帮我把社团活动和备赛内容相结合，使我可以兼顾。可以说，学校给予了我最需要的时间支持和精神支持。有了学校的支持，我便开始漫长的备赛过程。我的音乐专业老师陈老师指导我完善曲子、改进演奏技术。她给予我的，是专业知识和技能的支持。在决赛1月27日前的一个月，课题曲目公布。恰逢期末考试，我感受到前所未有的压力。为了能够完成我对音乐的追求，我几乎每天都睡得很晚很晚。期末考试结束之后，我全力冲刺，经常和老师沟通交流到深夜。那些天我每天近8个小时的持续练习，竭尽所能，完成编曲，为我的决赛铺路。 在日本东京比赛的当天，我非常紧张，甚至连饭都吃不下。等到主持人慢慢退下，我迈着坚定的步伐上台，耳朵里全都是我呼吸的声音。然而，我坐在琴上的那一刻，我突然感觉整个世界都安静了。手指放在琴键上，慢慢的，我的内心与琴键紧紧的连接起来了。学习音乐13年，我追求的那种享受终于降临在我身上。我用一个个连续有活力的音符，将两首曲子一气呵成地演奏出来，将我内心对于音乐的理解，那份热爱与追求倾诉出来。直到抬手结束，我的思绪依然沉浸在演奏当中。那一刻，我由衷地笑了，因为名次之于我，已经不重要了。我在音乐路上13年所追求的那种享受舞台的状态，在这次，完美地成为现实！YEF的舞台是我心目中梦想的舞台，没有什么比享受这个舞台重要，没有什么比享受音乐重要！从之前的万分紧张，到这一次淋漓尽致的音乐表现，足以见证我的成长，足以诠释这次比赛的意义！ 伴随我整个学期的2023YEF圆满的画上一个句号。回想这段路途，从7月的落地赛到1月的总决赛，心里真的有一种说不出来的感觉。谢谢大家一路的关心和支持！无论是来自父母和老师的指导、教诲，还是来自北京中学国际部同学们的每一声鼓励和支持。当然，我也要感谢我自己。谢谢我无数个深夜的坚持，谢谢我对音乐那至死不渝的热爱。这次YEF绝对不仅仅是一次比赛，它是我生命中闪闪发光的一笔！]]></summary></entry></feed>