<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-08-25T13:12:19+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Deconstructing a Classic: What Makes the Moog Minimoog Sound So Iconic?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/deconstructing-the-moog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deconstructing a Classic: What Makes the Moog Minimoog Sound So Iconic?"/><published>2024-05-15T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-15T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/deconstructing-the-moog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/deconstructing-the-moog/"><![CDATA[<p>The Minimoog Model D is more than just a synthesizer; it’s an icon. Its warm, powerful sound has graced thousands of records, from Parliament-Funkadelic to Kraftwerk. But what exactly gives it that character? It’s a combination of factors, starting with its three famously unstable voltage-controlled oscillators (VCOs). The slight drift between them creates a rich, phasing chorus effect that is instantly recognizable.</p> <p>However, the true heart of the Minimoog sound is its patented 4-pole (24 dB/octave) low-pass ladder filter. This is what gives the instrument its ability to produce deep, resonant basses and searing, expressive leads. The filter’s non-linear behavior when overdriven is a key part of its magic, adding a layer of saturation that digital emulations often struggle to replicate perfectly.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Synthesis"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A deep dive into the circuitry and design philosophy that gives the legendary Minimoog its timeless sound.]]></summary></entry></feed>